# WESLEY EL-AMIN

### WEB DEVELOPER

wesleye2003@gmail.com

• wesleyelamin.herokuapp.com

**\** 317-270-2208

in wesleyelamin

• wesleye2003

#### **About Me**

Through my background in sales and psychology I have developed a deep interest in interpersonal relationships; my love for connecting people and helping them solve their problems is what drives me. I also recently graduated a coding trade school called Dev Bootcamp as a full stack web developer. My experiences there vastly improved my ability and desire to learn new things on the fly, and gave me a new passion for creating fun and efficient teams where people can easily communicate, collaborate, and thrive. I also lead the development of a full-stack mobile application for musical collaboration using multiple current technologies and frameworks.

#### **Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer

**Dev Bootcamp** 

Chicago, IL Jan 2016 to May 2016

- Built proficiency in multiple programming languages including Ruby, JavaScript, and HTML.
- Worked individually and on teams of up to 5 to build many meaningful database-backed apps, websites, and programs.
- Came up with an idea for a mobile application and led a team that developed the app from scratch.
- Solved many code puzzles using object oriented programming and test driven development.
- Developed a much deeper knowledge of team dynamics and interpersonal relationships.
- Learned to develop, publish, and share open source software.

#### Sales Associate

**Micro Center** 

Columbus, OH May 2014 to May 2015

- Carried out regular cashier duties.
- Built a great amount of knowledge of computer parts, accessories, consumer electronics, networking systems, and more.
- Learned to troubleshoot various devices on the fly.
- Consistently exceeded \$1500 in sales each day and built a reputation as one of the highest performing salespeople in my department.

#### Front Desk Assistant

#### The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH Sep 2013 to Jan 2014

- Managed resident data in the student housing database.
- Empathized with residents and solved their problems as if they were my own.
- Assisted in planning community events.
- Assisted Resident Advisors and maintenance staff with the upkeep of the building.

#### **Projects**

#### Pick

Pick is an app that allows local musicians to connect with one another based on musical talents, preferred genre, and location. The app's front end was built in AngularJS and Ionic, and it provides an Android and iOS compatible user interface. The back end is built in Rails 4, and uses a zipcode API and Soundcloud's API for location filtering and user profile information. The back-end was tested with RSpec.

#### Bored? Games!

'Bored? Games!' is a web application that allows users to search through a database of board games using varying criteria. Users can also save games to their libraries, add other users as friends, give their favorite games 'points' to give them a positive rating, and view their friends' libraries of games. The application is a Ruby on Rails program that that is hosted on Heroku and uses a PostgreSQL database that was populated using Nokogiri and the board game geek API.

#### **Snack Overflow**

'Snack Overflow' is a clone of the popular developer forum, Stack Overflow, built using the Sinatra framework with a large amount of Ruby-based routing, Javascript(for AJAX calls and DOM updates using JQuery), and all data is stored in a SQLite3 database. Users can log in to post questions or topics of interest. Other logged in users can view those posts, vote 'up' or 'down' on them, and leave comments. Comments can also be voted up or down. Each post can also be created with tags; users can click on any of a post's tags to show all other posts that have that same tag. The search bar in the top left can be used to find posts by words they contain as well as tags.

#### **Skills**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Ruby

JavaScript

HTML5

CSS<sub>3</sub>

Sqlite3

Markdown

Ruby on Rails

PostgreSQL

Sinatra

Phaser.js

jQuery

**RSpec Testing** 

Jasmine Framework

Testing

**Capybara Testing** 

React

AngularJS

Ionic

PHP

WordPress

## PROGRAMMING PRINCIPLES

Object Oriented Design Pair Programming Test Driven Development Refactoring

#### OTHER SKILLS

Sales

Team Building

Microsoft Office

**Customer Service** 

Orchestral and Jazz Music Composition

Leadership

Troubleshooting

**Public Speaking** 

#### Education

Dev Bootcamp Web Development